sungard.com 2016-03-18

# Privacy Policy | SunGard

## SunGard’s Commitment to Privacy

SunGard Data Systems Inc. and each of its direct and indirect subsidiaries and controlled affiliates (“ **SunGard** ”) (“ **we** "”, “ **us** ”, or “ **our** ”) is committed to maintaining your confidence and trust, and accordingly we maintain the following Privacy and Cookie Policy (the “ **Policy** ”) to protect the personal information you provide online. To make this notice easy to find, we make it available from each page of this website (the “ **Website** ”). Please read the following carefully to understand our practices regarding your personal information collected through this Website. Questions regarding the Policy should be directed to [getinfo@sungard.com](mailto:getinfo@sungard.com).

This Policy is incorporated into and made a part of our Terms of Use.  As part of our Terms of Use, this Policy constitutes a legally binding agreement between you and us.  **By visiting or registering at the Website, you acknowledge that you have read, understand and agree to be bound by this Policy and the Terms of Use.   If you do not agree with the provisions of this Policy as they relate to the collection, transfer, storage and processing of your information, you may not access or use the Website.**

**Collection and Use of Information**

SunGard will only collect your personal information (such as your name, address, e-mail address or telephone number) via the Website if you provide it voluntarily. We may collect your personal information in a variety of ways on the Website.  For example, we may collect your name, email address, mailing address, and phone number when you create a profile under our “Careers” function. Should you choose to submit your CV for an open position, we will also collect any personal information contained in your CV.  We may also collect your name and email address if you use our “Contact Us” function, register for an event or request product literature or white papers. We use your personal information to create and register your account on the Website if you choose to do so, and also to review your qualifications or contact you if you are interested in applying for a job with us, to respond to your inquiries or requests, to invite you to events, to provide marketing materials to you, to provide you with the products and services you have requested, and to inform you about additional products or services that may be of interest to you. If you do not want this information to be collected and used by us, please do not submit it.

In addition, in the course of using the Website we automatically collect certain technical information about your visit. This information includes the URL of the website that you just came from (whether this URL is on the Website or not), which URL you go to next (whether this URL is on the Website or not), what Internet browser you are using, and your IP address. Many websites automatically collect this information from their visitors. We use this technical information to help us improve and personalize our services to you and for other internal purposes.

Your personal information collected through the Website will be available to all of SunGard for use and processing as provided in this Policy.  SunGard will not retain your personal information longer than we understand it is necessary for the purposes for which it is collected.

**Cookies**

We also use cookies to collect website usage data and to improve your experience on the Website. A “cookie” is a small data file transferred to your computer.  Some cookies are “session cookies” which means they are deleted when you close your browser; other cookies are “persistent” which means that they remain stored on your computer after you leave the Website and after you close your browser window.  The Website uses both session and persistent cookies. You have the ability to delete cookies from your hard drive at any time, or to avoid cookies by setting your Internet browser to reject them or to notify you when a cookie is being placed on your hard drive.  However, if you block cookies, you may not be able to use certain features on our Website and/or may be required to re-enter information more frequently to use certain services on the Website.  For more information about cookies generally, for example, how to control and delete cookies, please visit www.allaboutcookies.org.

Below is a summary of the types of cookies we use and why we use them. By using the Website, (without adjusting your Internet browser to block them), you agree that we can place these cookies on your device:

**Strictly Necessary:** These cookies are essential in enabling you to browse the Website and use its features. Without them, basic Website services cannot be provided or the functionality will be significantly impaired. 

**Performance Cookies:** These cookies collect anonymous information on how visitors use the Website and whether they encounter error messages from the Website. All information gathered is aggregated and therefore anonymized. They are used to improve how the Website works and to analyse trends (on an anonymized basis). 

**Functionality Cookies:** These cookies allow the Website to remember choices you make while browsing, like language, font size, and user name preferences and other customizable site elements. They may also be used to enable you to watch videos or post comments. The information associated with these cookies will not, by themselves, personally identify you.  When you choose these preferences, you agree that we can place these functional cookies on your device.

The Website also uses certain other web technologies, such as web beacons or other small snippets of code, which allow the Website to transfer or collect information.  These technologies are similar in purpose to cookies and are used, for example, to assist our email marketing services, and to measure marketing campaign effectiveness. 

**Disclosure and Sharing of Information**

SunGard occasionally hires other companies to provide services to SunGard or on our behalf where your information may be relevant.  These services include, for example, packaging and distributing products and information, assisting with event planning, registration and production, answering customer questions about products or services, and sending mail. SunGard may share your information with these companies for the purposes of delivering the service; our policy is to prohibit these service providers from using that information for any other purpose. 

We may also disclose your personal information to third parties not part of SunGard in the following instances: 

(1) in the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal information to the prospective buyer or seller; 

(2) if SunGard or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal information held by SunGard about its customers and others provided through the Website will be one of the transferred assets; 

(3) if we are required to do so by law or legal process; 

(4) in order to enforce or apply our Terms of Use; 

(5) to protect, defend or establish the rights, property or safety of SunGard, our customers, or others; or

(6) where you otherwise consent.

Other than what is described, SunGard’s policy is not to sell, trade or rent your personal information to others outside of SunGard companies and their advertising and promotional agencies and consultants. If you do not wish to receive marketing information, please contact us at [getinfo@sungard.com](mailto:getinfo@sungard.com).

**Transfers of Personal Information**

We collect, store and process the information from the Website in the United States of America. If you are outside the U.S., then your personal and non-personal information will be transferred to the U.S. and potentially to other countries where SunGard does business.  You should be aware that the data privacy and data protection laws outside your country may offer less protection than the laws in your country.  If you do not agree to such cross-border transfers of your personal data, please do not submit it through the Website. 

**Security**

SunGard has implemented commercially reasonable, technical and physical safeguards and appropriate security measures throughout the Website to protect your personal information against loss, misuse or unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction. Please be advised, however, that although SunGard has endeavored to create a secure and reliable website for you, the confidentiality of any communication or material transmitted to or from SunGard via the Website or e-mail cannot be guaranteed. When disclosing any personal information, you should remain mindful of the fact that it is potentially accessible to the public, and consequently can be collected and used by others without your consent. SunGard has no responsibility or liability for the security of information transmitted via the Internet.

**External Websites**

To the extent that you access third party sites (e.g., social networks) from our Website, you should be aware that these third party sites are not controlled by SunGard and, therefore, are not subject to this Policy. You should check the privacy policies of these third party sites to see how your personal information will be utilized by the operators of those third party sites.

**Direct Marketing, Access and Correction**

Our policy is to inform you if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for direct marketing purposes by the third party. You may be entitled to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your information. You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at [getinfo@sungard.com](mailto:mailto:getinfo@sungard.com). 

Depending on the requirements of your local law, you may have the right to access the personal information which SunGard has collected about you, and you could also have the right to review it, and to modify any errors contained in that information.  As permitted by law, we may request a fee for handling and responding to such requests. Please contact us [getinfo@sungard.com](mailto:getinfo@sungard.com) for more details.

**California Residents**

California law permits our users who are California residents to request and obtain from us once a year, free of charge, information about the personally identifiable information (if any) we disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year. If applicable, this information would include a list of the categories of personal information that were shared and the names and addresses of all third parties with which we shared information in the immediately preceding calendar year. If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please submit your request in writing to [getinfo@sungard.com](mailto:getinfo@sungard.com).  This will not prohibit disclosure of the information for non-marketing purposes.

**Changes to this Privacy and Cookie Policy**

SunGard may modify this Policy from time to time without prior notice to you. If we decide to change the Policy, we will post those changes on this page and will indicate at the top of the Policy when it was most recently updated. Your continued use of the Website following the posting of changes to these terms will mean you accept these changes. 

**Your Consent**

By using the Website, you consent to the collection, use and transfer of your information by SunGard as described, including the use of cookies and web technologies.    

**How to Contact Us**

Should you have other questions or concerns about this Policy, please email [getinfo@sungard.com](mailto:getinfo@sungard.com).

Copyright © 2015 SunGard Data Systems Inc. All rights reserved.
